<resources>
    <string name="app_name">FolkecenterMobileApp</string>
    <!--MAIN PAGE STRINGS-->
    <string name="main_page_title">Nordic Folkecenter</string>
    <string name="grid_news">Recent News</string>
    <string name="grid_events">Upcoming Events</string>
    <string name="grid_guided_tour">Guided Tour</string>
    <string name="grid_map">Interactive Map</string>
    <string name="grid_history">Our History</string>
    <string name="grid_tips">Sustainable Tips</string>
    <string name="grid_training">Training</string>
    <string name="grid_quiz">Quiz Game</string>


    <!--RECENT NEWS PAGE STRINGS-->
    <string name="news_read_more">Read More</string>
    <string name="news_subtitle_date">Date</string>
    <string name="news_title">Title</string>

    <!--GUIDED TOUR PAGE STRINGS-->
    <string name="guided_tour_title">Guided Tour</string>
    <string name="grid_test_field">Test Field</string>
    <string name="grid_biodome">Biodome</string>
    <string name="grid_cafe_solaire">Cafe Solaire</string>
    <string name="grid_workshop">Workshop</string>
    <string name="grid_plus_house">Plus House</string>
    <string name="grid_passive_house">Passive House</string>
    <string name="grid_skibstedfjord">SkibstedFjord</string>
    <string name="grid_water_treatment">Water Treatment</string>
    <string name="grid_oil_lab">Plant Oil Lab</string>
    <string name="grid_wind_museum">Wind Museum</string>
    <string name="grid_floating_foundation">Floating Foundation</string>

    <!--TEST FIELD PAGE STRINGS-->
    <string name="test_field_title">Test Field</string>
    <string name="test_field_audio_tour">Test Field Audio Tour</string>
    <string name="test_field_text_tour_title">Audio Tour Transcription</string>
    <string name="test_field_text_tour">The location of Folkecenter (strong and frequent winds) makes it the ideal location for testing small wind turbines. Folkecenter’s testfield is includes different models and components on test, from different manufacturers around the world. The test field has:Standard foundations for wind turbines up to 75 kW.Location for 10 small wind turbines up to 10 kW.Internal cable connections for electricity and measurements.Measuring masts.3 wells (6 meters deep) for testing of wind pumps.Containers for measuring equipment and supplies.Tests of wind turbines from 60 watts up to 90 kW have been conducted for Danish and foreign companies.Since 1984 the 75 kW blue wind turbine has supplied Folkecenter with electricity. The turbine, designed by Folkecenter, was meant as starting building block for companies willing to enter the wind market. Together with other models of the DAN series, the turbine has a documentation which is accessible for those searching for a reliable model to enter the wind business.Folkecenter has now a new test field, located in Hundborg. More information can be found on the link below:
https://smallwind.dk/
</string>

    <!--BIODOME PAGE STRINGS-->
    <string name="biodome_title">Biodome</string>
    <string name="biodome_audio_tour">Biodome Audio Tour</string>
    <string name="biodome_text_tour">The Biodome has 3 floors. The inner diameter of the floor plan is 14.4 meters and the largest inner diameter (floor plan at 1st floor) is 15.5 meters. The building is constructed with a skeleton of aluminum pipes, which are covered with 3-layer polycarbonate sheets. The building is manufactured in Colorado, USA and was established in 1992.
The floor plan is equipped with plant beds and with two 23 m3 water pools. The pools are the key of the system: the Azolla plants floating on the surface purify the rain water and act as food for fishes. The fishes than produce manure, which enriches the water. Finally, the water is used to irrigate the plants, making the whole process free of chemical fertilizers.
The 1st floor is furnished with plant beds with 50m2 cultivated soils. An automatic time-controlled irrigation system is also present.
Without the addition of heat other than solar energy, there is a Mediterranean climate in the Biodome, all year round. During summer, the top floor can reach even higher temperatures, allowing to grow plants typical of warmer climates.
 The Biodome is a so-called minimal construction with a light-bearing skeleton. Plant cultivation is possible for up to 10 months a year. In the coldest winter days there may be light frost at night, but the pools will not freeze.
The Biodome demonstrates how to integrate water circuits, recycling nutrient salts and soil and aquaculture.
</string>

    <!--CAFE SOLAIRE PAGE STRINGS-->
    <string name="cafe_solaire_title">Cafe Solaire</string>
    <string name="cafe_solaire_audio_tour">Cafe Solaire Audio Tour</string>

    <!--WORKSHOP PAGE STRINGS-->
    <string name="workshop_title">Workshop</string>
    <string name="workshop_audio_tour">Workshop Audio Tour</string>

    <!--PLUS HOUSE PAGE STRINGS-->
    <string name="plus_house_title">Plus House</string>
    <string name="plus_house_audio_tour">Plus House Audio Tour</string>
    <string name="plus_house_text_tour">With a floor area of 600 m2, the building was constructed in 1992 by Folkecenter with support of the EU and the Danish Energy Agency. The Plus Energy House is a test house that produces more energy than it uses itself; it is composed of many different individual components, each of which has proven their efficiency.The house has a shape of a large solar collector: the south-facing facade consists of two layers of glass with 20cm between each layer; polystyrene balls stored in the silos behind the building can be injected in the façade, allowing to have insulation only when needed (for example, during the night), but also allowing to provide shade to the whole building, or part of it and, in this way, to control indoor climate. The house is also equipped with a heat pump.There are different temperature levels at the different floors: during a sunny summer day, the top floor can reach over 50°C. It has been documented through measuring that the house can deliver more heat to the district heating system of Folkecenter than it is supplied in the form of electricity to the heat pump, reason for which the house is called Plus Energy House.</string>

    <!--PASSIVE HOUSE PAGE STRINGS-->
    <string name="passive_house_title">Passive House</string>
    <string name="passive_house_audio_tour">Passive House Audio Tour</string>
    <string name="passive_house_text_tour">The term Passive House refers to the fact that the house does not, in principle, need to be supplied with energy for neither heating nor cooling. This means that there is virtually no heat loss, and that the building is optimized to utilize the heat supply that occurs through solar radiation and human activity. The Definition of a passive house is:
(1)The energy consumption for space heating is at a maximum of 15 kWh/m2.
(2)The total energy consumption is at a maximum of 120 kWh/m2.
(3)Air tightness: Maximum 0.6/h air change.
Note that the m2 is considered interior and not exterior, which is normal in Denmark.Architectural heat loss can be minimized by minimizing the buildings surface, as it is known from traditional Danish construction practice. To utilize the passive solar heat, the houses windows and living rooms are oriented to the south. Good daylight conditions are crucial for both the comfort of the house and for lower energy consumption.Constructively, heat loss is avoided by means of a thick and close insulation without thermal bridges, as well as the use of windows and doors with very low U-value, and more.Note how windows and doors are mounted in the insulating layer and only partially in the lightweight concrete wall. The lightweight concrete walls are chosen because of their thermal accumulation properties.Finally, the mechanical ventilation and heat recovery is a special feature of the Passive House.This ensures a continuous airflow through the house, where the fresh cool outdoor air is heated with the heat from the "used" indoor air.Price:In addition to the energy requirements, the house tests the possibility of reducing building expenses, normally quite high for passive houses. The present building has a m2 price of a maximum of 10,000 DKK, including VAT for materials and crafts expenses. The smaller the building area, the larger the relative surface of the climate screen (roof and outer walls) and the more difficult it is to keep the square meter price down.The Passive House here at the Folkecenter is the smallest passive house in Denmark so far (100 m2). The low price is achieved by building a very simple house.The efforts to minimize the building surface mean not only that heat loss is reduced but also a reduction of material costs.Labor-intensive details are avoided. The unilateral slope of the roof is completely without penetration to the chimney, ventilation, windows and more. The house has four perpendicular corners and no bay windows, niches or extensions. The number of windows is limited to a few rooms.Other economic solutions include prefabricated light concrete walls, the terrain deck insulation material, roof and outer wall steel sheet cladding and, in particular, the absence of central heating systems.Moreover, the costs of electricity and ventilation are almost the same as in new buildings.Environment:To the extent that it has been possible within the given energy and economic framework, it is sought to use environmentally friendly materials, as well as local suppliers and craftsmen.Thus, paper wool is the main component of ceiling and wall insulation. Waterproofed wood has only been used where it has been necessary, which means hardly any.The choice of woods like larch and pine tree in a good quality is crucial to this being possible.There is access to the Passive House by appointment. Ask at the reception.
</string>

    <!--SKIBSTEDFJORD PAGE STRINGS-->
    <string name="skibsted_fjord_title">Skibstedfjord</string>
    <string name="skibsted_fjord_audio_tour">Skibstedfjord Audio Tour</string>
    <string name="skibsted_fjord_text_tour">Built in 1996 and with an area of 750m2, SkibstedFjord is Denmarks first underground test house. In Thy, it is called Jordhuset (the Turf House). It is built into a hill with a facade towards the beautiful Skibsted Fjord. The special architecture is used to make the house invisible in the landscape, following the principles of the so called “Invisible Architecture”.
The house demonstrates that you can lay a large building in a natural area without dominating it.
The house is enclosed by soil on three of its sides, and is covered by 1.5 meters of earth.
All the soil-covered surfaces are sealed with bentonite, a volcanic soil species from Wyoming, USA. Bentonite swells 100 times when it meets water, and by that way seals the house.
Since the construction of the house, no moisture has been detected in any of the outer walls, even though the house is exposed to significant water pressure.
The house contains an octagonal meeting room that seats 200 people, a kitchen, study rooms and library. The supporting building parts are made of concrete, which is molded on site.
The energy consumption is very low:
3 types of passive solar heat systems have been used.
Finnish masonry oven with stove (Denmarks largest).
2 kinds of window-integrated photovoltaics (Denmarks first).
Photovoltaics of the thin film type in the facade band.
Heat pump and underfloor heating.
In 1996, the first 680 m2 costed 4.5 million DKK, with a square meter price of 6600 DKK.
The entrance portal was added in 2001 and all the craftsmen were all local.
Preben Maegaard developed the concept of the house, inspired by the octagonal assembly house in Galtrup on Mors.
Architect: Møller Nielsen Tegnestue (Design Office), Struer, v/arkitekt MAA Per Clausen.
Engineer: Viggo Øhlenschlæger, Sdr. Ydby.
Financing: Financial legislation grant from 1992.
Client: Property Fund Landsbyen for Grøn Forskning (Village for Green Research).
</string>

    <!--WATER TREATMENT PAGE STRINGS-->
    <string name="water_treatment_title">Water Treatment</string>
    <string name="water_treatment_audio_tour">Water Treatment Audio Tour</string>
    <string name="water_treatment_text_tour">The Folkecenters latest plant for organic wastewater treatment, which is called Water-For-Life, is intended for a single household.It is divided into 2 experimental plants, which are realistic alternatives to conventional wastewater removal. It is based on ecological principles with the sun as an energy source.Air is blown in to oxygenate the wastewater. The plant then utilizes the nutrients in the waste water for the production of a new biomass, after which the sewage can be recycled for outdoor watering, lavatory flushing and the like.The Water-For-Life plant is easy to manufacture: only widely available and already industrial mass produced materials such as pipes, hoses, containers and pumps are used. The plastic containers can also be alternatively replaced with concrete.The plant works as long as the temperature is above 12 degrees.</string>

    <!--PLANT OIL LAB PAGE STRINGS-->
    <string name="plant_oil_lab_title">Plant Oil Lab</string>
    <string name="plant_oil_lab_audio_tour">Plant Oil Lab Audio Tour</string>
    <string name="plant_oil_lab_text_tour">Since 1994, the Folkecenter has been working on plant oil for transport. There are several types of plant oil, depending on the seeds used. To be as sustainable as possible, seeds should come from locally-grown plants, so using avocado seeds in Denmark would not be a good idea. The best crop for this application in Denmark is rapeseed, which is grown mostly for feeding animals.
Out of 3 kg of rapeseed, 2 kg are of protein-rich seed cake (used for animals) and 1 kg is oil, which is equivalent to approximately 1.1 liters. The oil yield is therefore limited and it often raises questions concerning the sustainability of PPO and biofuels in general. However, something not often considered is that the leftovers of the plant become straw, which in Denmark is used for heat and power production. The energy output per hectare is, therefore, much higher than the one related to oil production alone.
Nevertheless, PPO is not the solution for all transportation: pipe emissions are approximately the same than those from conventional Diesel vehicles, so the only saving is in terms of processes: PPO does not need to be extracted, refined or transport from other parts of the world, making it more environmentally friendly. To be sustainable it has, however, to be kept local, maybe for those applications for which electric engines are still not suitable (for example, in tractors).
Concerning costs, German examples show that pressing accounts for approx. 1 DKK per kilo of oil, including investment, wages and process energy. The process energy is approx. 100-150 kWh / ton of oil, which corresponds to the energy content of 10-15 liters of oil.
Rape seed costs approx. 2 DKK per kilo, and the seed cakes value is approx. 1.2 DKK per kilo.
This means that the raw material price will be approx. DKK 3.45 per liter, which, in addition to the cost of pressing, gives a total production price of approx. DKK 4.45 per liter.
 In addition, VAT and taxes, distribution and profits should be added, making PPO comparable and, in some cases, slightly more expensive than Diesel.
The oil press can produce 2-4 liters of rapeseed oil per hour, depending on the quality of the rapeseed. In addition to oil, the press also produces seed cakes, which can be used to feed animals, due to their high protein content.
</string>

    <!--WIND MUSEUM LAB PAGE STRINGS-->
    <string name="wind_museum_title">Wind Museum</string>
    <string name="wind_museum_audio_tour">Wind Museum Audio Tour</string>
    <string name="wind_musem_text_tour">The wind museum is a witness of wind turbines development and it includes a collection of wind turbines and related components from 1975.The many different models illustrate the technological development that has taken place over the years, which allowed Denmark to become a leading country in the field.The exhibition contains unique examples from the Danish wind turbine history, some of which are prototypes, meaning that only this copy is available.Among the exhibited items are the largest wooden wings that are made in Denmark.They were used on the Nibe A wind turbines  and on "Den Gule Enke (The Yellow Widow)" developed by the Folkecenter. They are 13 m long and they were able to produce 150 kW (equivalent to 150 washing machines). Blades are now much longer, with lengths reaching 107 m and power production capacities up to 12 MW (12.000 washing machines). They are built in fiberglass and they are much more flexible than the ones in wood. The museum is the largest wind collection in Denmark. The building was built in 2001 and it is a standard hall that was modified by Kenneth Olsen, MAA, for the present purpose. The load bearing structure is lattice of wood. The external timbering is of pine tree from Estonia, painted with "Falu Rödfärg” (Falu red color), Swedish copper oxide paint.It costed 600.000 DKK to construct the hall, which is 15 x 30 meters.</string>


    <!--FLOATING FOUNDATION PAGE STRINGS-->
    <string name="floating_foundation_title">Floating Foundation</string>
    <string name="floating_foundation_audio_tour">Floating Foundation Audio Tour</string>
    <string name="floating_foundation_text_tour">The model is entirely the result of the work of Folkecenter trainees, from the design to the actual construction and testing. The model represents in scale the solutions which are now being considered in the industry of offshore wind turbines, to overcome the challenges posed by deep seawaters. The whole process was carried out between 2019 and 2020 by different groups of trainees and the concept has been tested in the local fjord. The floating foundation is now being connected to a small wind turbine which powers an LED installation. Blades, tower, foundation and LED illumination have all been developed and constructed by the trainees.</string>

    <!--QUIZ GAME PAGE STRINGS-->
    <string name="quiz_game_title">Folkecenter Quiz Game</string>
    <string name="quiz_game_instructions">Currently the Folkecenter Quiz Game is not available on mobile devices and can only be played on desktop platforms. Follow the link below for installation.</string>
    <string name="quiz_game_button">Open Game Link</string>

    <!--TRAINING PAGE STRINGS-->
    <string name="training_title">Training Program</string>
    <string name="training_text">We offer a wide range of training and education programmes and activities meant to meet the main needs of current and future professionals in the field. Workshops, conferences, renewable energy courses or the trainee programme are some of the examples.</string>
    <string name="training_button">More Details</string>

    <!--TIPS PAGE STRINGS-->
    <string name="tips_title">Sustainable Tips</string>
    <string name="main_tips_text">Saving the planet sounds huge doesn’t it? And in essence, it is. But there are many simple ways you can do your bit to help. Check out this list of easy ways to go green and do your bit to help! These are steps that anyone can and should take to help reduce the effect of years of abuse.</string>
    <string name="open_tips_button">Open Tips</string>
    <string name="tip_no1_title">Tip #1</string>
    <string name="tip_no1_text">Energy efficient lightbulbs are a simple way to reduce the amount of power you use. Not only will this help the planet, it will also save your bank balance too. By replacing just one lightbulb, the effect can be tremendous. If every house in Europe did this, it would reduce pollution by the same amount as removing two million cars from the road!</string>
    <string name="tip_no2_title">Tip #1</string>
    <string name="tip_no3_title">Tip #2</string>
    <string name="tip_no4_title">Tip #3</string>
    <string name="tip_no5_title">Tip #4</string>
    <string name="tip_no6_title">Tip #5</string>
    <string name="tip_no7_title">Tip #6</string>
    <string name="tip_no8_title">Tip #7</string>
    <string name="tip_no9_title">Tip #8</string>
    <string name="tip_no10_title">Tip #9</string>
    <string name="tip_no2_text">Unless it’s absolutely essential, for example if you’re making bread, you don’t need to pre-heat the oven. You can just set it away when you are ready to start cooking. Bonus tip: When checking the food, look through the door rather than opening it until the final check.</string>
    <string name="tip_no3_text">You don’t have to give up meat for life, but try to commit to one meat free day a week. It takes 18,000 liters of water to produce a single kilogram of beef. And each hamburger that comes from animals on ex-forestry ground is responsible for the destruction of fifty-five square feet of forest.</string>
    <string name="tip_no4_text">If your car has a cruise control, then do use it! You paid for it along with the car anyway. This will help to improve your mileage at least by 15%, which will in the process save the environment, gasoline and your wallet.</string>
    <string name="tip_no5_text">A lot of things can be sourced second hand. Things that have a short usage period due to growth, for example, a child’s bicycle, can be picked up second hand in fantastic condition and also at a fraction of the price. This saves you money and helps to reduce packaging materials.</string>
    <string name="tip_no6_text">Make sure to recycle your old newspapers - 69% (or 44 million newspapers) of the newspapers printed in the USA are thrown away every day. Even if you recycle only once per week, half a million trees could be saved. Or even better, why not avoid newspapers altogether and read the online versions!</string>
    <string name="tip_no7_text">Switching your bath for a shower can make a huge difference. Baths use approximately double the amount of water a shower uses. This not only saves water, but it saves you money on heating the excess water too.</string>
    <string name="tip_no8_text">Adjusting the temperature in your home by just one degree can save you 10% on your energy use over the year. This is another great saving you and another great help for the planet. Where possible, set a timer so your heating/cooling doesn’t need to be on when you aren’t home.</string>
    <string name="tip_no9_text">Plastic carrier bags are not biodegradable, nor are they recyclable. They sit in landfills where they often end up polluting the ocean and infiltrating food sources. Use a stronger, reusable bag.</string>
    <string name="tip_no10_text">Bottled water is handy when you’re on the go, but why not buy one bottle and then refill it from the tap or your work’s water cooler. Around 90% of water bottles end up decomposing in landfills rather than being recycled.</string>

    <!--LANGUAGE SELECT PAGE STRINGS-->
    <string name="language_select_title">Select language</string>
</resources>
